in this lecture we're going to learn about Amazon Q Business.
So what is Amazon Q Business?
Amazon Q Business is a fully managed,
generative AI powered assistant.
So the core objective of Amazon Q Business
is to improve the productivity of an employee.
So how does Amazon Q improve the productivity of an employee
by helping generate content
which can act as a baseline for the business user.
Then it can summarize data.
So most employees have to go through
a large number of documents, reports and so on.
So what it can do is it can summarize the data
for the employees and improve its productivity.
A lot of times let's say you are a marketing manager
or a sales manager, you need to go through
a large number of different organization data sources
to come up with maybe a proposal
or a brand campaign and so on.
So you will have to go through all the different data sources
may be some data is in the Salesforce,
some is in the database, some is in the Google Drive.
So what Amazon Q allows you is to chat with enterprise data.
So you can have a chat based interface
and then you can post query irrespective of where the data
is whether it's in the Google Drive S3 Salesforce.
It will give you a response that is relevant to you.
Then it also has plugins such as GRA, ServiceNow, et cetera,
where you could give the commands in natural language
and say create a ticket for the task
and it will automatically go ahead and create a task
in the GRA or ServiceNow for you.
You can think of Amazon Q as a chat GPT
with enterprise controls.
Now let's try and understand how Amazon Q for business
can improve the productivity by taking a look
at a typical day of a marketing manager.
So let's say we have a marketing manager
that works in a large Fortune 500 company
and her name is Anisha.
Now the objective of the organization
is to improve the productivity of Anisha with Amazon Q.
Now let's see what are the four key tasks for Anisha
in a day and how Amazon Q can help.
Now let's say the first one is she got a feedback report
on the impact of marketing campaign
and it's about 20 pages long.
They had launched a campaign few weeks back
and now they have got a feedback report.
Now Amazon Q can help summarize this 20 page report
into maybe a couple of pages
which will help improve the productivity of Anisha
to some extent.
Now let's say the second task for her today is
she wants to send an email to a prospective client
outlying the steps to launch a campaign for a juice trick
and again Amazon Q can help you by generating
draft content for her.
Then let's say she wants to understand
what are the brand guidelines within the organization
because she is new to the organization
and these brand guidelines are spread across
large number of enterprise data sources
maybe some are in SharePoint, some others are in Salesforce
and so on.
So Amazon Q has a chat interface through which you can ask
queries to Amazon Q and it's going to search all the
enterprise data sources and give back a response to you.
And then finally let's say she wants to assign some tasks
to her direct report is Amazon Q provides you
with a plugin through which you can write the task
in natural language in the chat interface
and it's going to create a ticket in the zero.
Okay, now let's take a quick look at Amazon Q
for business architecture.
Okay, now there are two type of users for Amazon Q.
One is the admin user which manages the application
allows you to connect with different data sources
within the enterprise ads users and groups to the application
and deletes and so on.
And then you have the end user.
Okay, now we have the Amazon Q application
and it can connect to large number of different enterprise
data sources sometimes call us reviewers.
So there are more than 40 pre-built connectors.
So you have the S3, RDS, Google Drive, Salesforce
and many others as we'll see in the demo.
So first thing you'll have to do while building an app
on Amazon Q is to identify the data sources
and then Amazon Q will ingest the document contents
and permissions on who has access to these documents.
Then Amazon Q also supports large number of plugins
like Jira and ServiceNow.
You can establish connection with Jira and ServiceNow.
So once you have accomplished this task
of connecting the Amazon Q with the data source and plugins,
the next thing you need to do is you need to connect it
with some form of authentication and authorization
and that is done using the IM Identity Center
where this admin will create the users
and groups that will have access to Amazon Q
from the end user perspective.
Okay, now let's say you have created the users and groups.
Now let's say we have this business user Anisha
who is a marketing manager and she is a query regarding
what are the branding guidelines within the organization.
And let's say they are within this PDF in the S3 bucket.
So once she sends the query to Amazon Q,
Amazon Q will validate her authentication credentials
and group permissions, then it will refer to the document
on what are the kind of permissions
that are highlighted in this document
that she's seeking to access where the query.
And if the permissions match,
then she's going to get back a response
and it could be a filter response.
If her permissions that have been defined
in the IM Identity Center does not match to the permission
that are required to access this document.
So hopefully the business architecture for Amazon Q
is clear to you, I'll see you in the next lecture.
Thank you.